So I'm going to take these pants over and go ahead and press them down.
And I'm going to show you how we're going to mark where we're going to cut off the pants.
So let's go over here to my work table/ironing table, and here we go.
So the first thing I want to do is go ahead and iron this down, just like I did the other leg, just kind of pull it a tiny bit, there we go.
I'm just going to iron right here along the seam.
And like I said before, I like do that just because I know the fabric is right were it's supposed to be, and you give it that little press.
Now this side, okay.
Then we're going to open it and get that crease that I put there, out.
I'm going to do the inside also.
Okay, because we've already done this once, so I'm just going to get after and do it.
Okay, so now that I have this pressed down, I'm going to go ahead and flip these pants back out, because I need to see that excess fabric, so I can determine where I'm going to cut it off.
Okay, here we go.
And when I do this, if I have to cut off the fabric I like to leave about an inch excess fabric in the inside.
And that's a good idea just in case, say someone else wants to wear them, they'll have a little bit to work with.
If they need to let the hem out, because you can still let the pants out and still have some original hem left.
So, I'm just going to start right here where I put that one little seam that I sewed myself, and mark 1 inch.
Here we go.
And on this side, and also on the next side.
Okay, it's all the way around.
So, in a minute I'm going to show you how, I'm going to talk about it and show you how we're going to trim this off.
And I'll show you how to do that next.